# Gonzalo Reyes

A software engineer enthusiast who enjoys solving real-world problems related to community building, finance and education. Currently, working toward the improvement of the learning experience of students at SUNY Plattsburgh through convenient and sophisticated software applications

#### **EDUCATION**

# State University of New York at Plattsburgh

PLATTSBURGH, NY - AUGUST 2016 - PRESENT (EXPECTED MAY 2020)

- Computer Science B.S | GPA: 3.88
- Honors: Academic Achievement in Computer Science (Spring '18)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Codecademy / Software Engineer Intern**

NEW YORK, NY — JUNE 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- Co-engineered the new *Code Challenges* feature, an assessment type that allows learners to type and execute code to reinforce their knowledge
- Demoed the Code Challenges MVP to the company stakeholders in the monthly all-hands meeting
- Took initiative and stepped forward to contribute to the migration of React components and Javascript files to Typescript
- Collaborated with designers and engineers to launch a new <u>interactive 404</u>
  page that renders a custom endless runner game built with PhaserJS
- Worked on frontend improvements including redesigning the footer and catalog, converting legacy .erb pages to react and fixing accessibility bugs
- Reviewed and tested production-ready code. Utilized Jest and Enzyme for unit and component testing, TestCafe for E2E testing and RSpec for rails

#### Coding Hub / Co-founder, President, and Lead Engineer

PLATTSBURGH, NY - SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

- Spearhead an agile team of 20 members to plan, build, test and deploy 4 software apps to assist students and organizations on campus
- Establish coding standards and write detailed documentation to make applications maintainable and allow new members to quickly understand and collaborate on the projects
- Successfully explain highly-technical concepts to university staff to gain approval and receive support to deploy our applications
- Conduct bi-weekly stand-up meetings and encourage team collaboration through code reviews, pair programming, and weekly lightning talks
- Introduce and set up CI/CD pipeline with CircleCI in our workflow to improve development speed and ensure code quality
- Introduce and use Slack and Asana for team and project management

#### **Interbank / Data Analyst Intern**

LIMA, PE - JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2018

- Developed a supervised ML classifier with python to categorize customer reviews with an accuracy of 92% as measured by a confusion matrix
- Built 15 fully responsive banners for the mobile app and website using HTML5, CSS3, and vanilla JS to do A/B testing and test experiments
- Proactively participated in weekly committee meetings of 5 people to show and analyze tests results as well as propose and discuss new experiments

reyesegonzalo@gmail.com

www.iamgonchi.com

https://github.com/gonzen2310

www.linkedin.com/in/gonzalo-reyes

(518) 466 - 1229

#### **LANGUAGES**

Java, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Kotlin, C++, TypeScript, Dart, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

#### SKILLS

Web development, Android, UI/UX, Github, Project Manager, Algorithms, Teaching

#### TOP PROJECTS

# **Shuttler** / Lead Android Engineer

App that locates the college shuttles in real-time

- Designed prototype using AdobeXD
- Built Android app with Kotlin and Java
- Used Firebase Auth to authenticate users, Cloud Firestore to manage real-time data, and Cloud Functions to send notifications
- Integrated Google Maps API to display shuttle location and monitor geofences
- Utilized Android Jetpack components and tools to develop a robust MVVM application
- Rendered Adobe AE animations with Lottie

### Tutoring Hub / PM & Lead Engineer

Website to rate academic tutors on Campus

- Designed and developed Single Page
  Application with React + Typescript
- Integrated Redux for UI state management
- Built a RESTful API with Express.js and MongoDB that serves data to the front-end
- Integrated Cloudinary SDK to host and manage static media assets
- Wrote a python script to populate DB by parsing a CSV file with a list of active tutors
- Utilized Jest for unit testing and Enzyme for React component testing

#### OneSpot / Full-stack Developer

Web app that helps you track job applications

- Architected a monolith Rails GraphQL API that communicates with a React front-end
- Leveraged React ecosystem by using Hooks and Context API to manage states
- Integrated Apollo client to query back-end
- Utilized React beautiful DnD for smooth drag and drop interactions
- Designed an ER diagram with Lucidchart and created a database with Postgresql